<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Almost Perceptive</title>
    <link>http://almostperceptive.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Almost Perceptive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://almostperceptive.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The (99%) Invisible Hand</title>
      <link>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/the-invisible-hand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/the-invisible-hand/</guid>
      <description>How inequality makes bad design It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that the West has a inequality problem. Since 1980, the share of overall income going to the top 1% of earners in the US, UK and Australia has increased sharply. In fact, the economist Thomas Piketty has even gone so far to say that the US has a level of inequality &amp;lsquo;probably higher than in any other society at any time in the past, anywhere in the world&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all machines.</title>
      <link>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/social-media/</guid>
      <description>The worst offence of social media is the theft of the capacity for reverie - Richard Seymour Since we&amp;rsquo;ve all been spending a lot more time indoors, social media has become a lot more important for a lot of us. It offered an escape from the empty streets and time-stopped storefronts and reminded us that things continued to happen, bad things, mostly, as the death tolls continued to rise.
The contrast between things never fails to amaze me, especially on the major social networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You know, if the protagonist is happy, there’s no story at all.</title>
      <link>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/magical-realism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/magical-realism/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;When I’m writing novels, reality and unreality just naturally get mixed together&amp;rsquo; - Haruki Murakami I&amp;rsquo;ve recently finished reading Haruki Murakami&amp;rsquo;s Killing Commedatore, and wanted to explore the themes of magical realism further. To be clear, magical realism is not the same as fantasy; In a very simple nutshell, magical realism is what happens when a highly detailed, realistic setting is invaded by something too strange to believe. The genre itself has certain political connotations, especially with those who believe that it should remain strongly connected to its Latin-American roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The aphorism is already a shadow of itself.</title>
      <link>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/a-shadow-of-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/a-shadow-of-itself/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;The eternal silence of these endless spaces terrifies me.&amp;rsquo; - Blaise Pascal In Andrew Hui&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;lsquo;A Theory of the Aphorism&amp;rsquo; (which you can purchase here), he describes aphorisms as a phrase which &amp;lsquo;condenses&amp;rsquo;. It transforms a epic into a book, a book into a page, and a page into a single, pithy phrase that can be thought upon and pondered over, relentlessly. Hui picks six key thinkers as representative of his theories on aphorism - three &amp;lsquo;ancients&amp;rsquo;, three &amp;lsquo;moderns&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything must have a beginning.</title>
      <link>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 12:05:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://almostperceptive.com/posts/the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;There are things known and there are things unknown, and in between are the doors of perception.&amp;rsquo; - Aldous Huxley. It&amp;rsquo;s always difficult to begin something, I find. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to declare to yourself, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to do that thing that I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to start&amp;hellip; wait for it&amp;hellip; now!&amp;rsquo; You might get a warm glow for a little while, flush with your own decisiveness and go-getter attitude, but in the heat of the moment, you never actually get around to doing anything at all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>